# ROHAN UDAS

Data Analyst | Data Scientist | Business Consulting

(91) 96 896 696 28 • udasrohan@gmail.com • www.rohanudas.in

## ABOUT ME

I have 3.8 years of experience in advanced analytical techniques like Data Mining & Visualizing, Forecasting, Predictive modeling and statistical software & packages of Python, R Studio, SQL, Tableau, Power BI, and SPSS. Functional experience in transforming the business problem into the strategic advanced analytical problem.

### EDUCATION

2020 - 2023 • Symbiosis International University Executive MBA (Business Analytics)

2019 - 2020 • Maharashtra state board Post-graduation Diploma (PGD), Data Science

2014 - 2017 • Pune University Bachelor of Electrical Engineering

### EXPERIENCE

#### HiTech iSolutions LLP

## Data Analyst Sep 2020 - till date

- Sales Forecasting of Food Products -Achieved 90% accuracy in the forecast for next 3 months horizon
- Smart Demand Forecasting -Applied econometrics along with advanced modeling
- Twitter Analysis Brand / Product / Feature sentiment analysis
- Recommendation engine -Promotion recommendation as per the market demand
- Market Basket Analysis Analysis of uncovering associations between items and brands

## • Jiangyin Uni-Pol Vacuum Casting India Private limited

### Project Engineer (Aug 2017 - Sep 2020)

- Data Analysis of Production & Process data -maximum production at optimized process parameter
- Inventory Planning -Minimizing inventory waiting time
- Yield management system Dynamic Yield management to get the maximum use of man, machine and material
- Production shop Dashboarding Used for live production monitoring with KPI indication
- Predictive maintenance -Planning the maintenance of the machine from historical data and usage

## EXPERTISE

- · Forecasting Models
- Regression
- Classification
- Ensemble Algorithms
- Data Visualization
- Time Series Analysis & Forecasting
- Data Mining
- · Data Cleaning
- R Studio
- · Machine Learning
- Python
- SPSS
- · Statistical models
- Bagging & Boosting
- · Sentiment Analysis
- · SQL and NoSQL
- Microsoft Excel

## CERTIFICATION

- AI For Everyone Deeplearning.ai
- Machine Learning Foundation University of Washington
- Python Project for Data Science- IBM
- Business Analytics for Decision Making- University of Colorado
- Exploratory Data Analysis Johns Hopkins university
- Business analytics Course IMS Proschool
- SQL Fundamentals Sololearn
- Tableau Fundamentals- Tableau Software
- Power BI Essential training LinkedIn learning
- Advance Machine Learning & Artificial Intelligence IMS Proschool

### RESEARCH DOMAIN

• Demand forecasting in food industry

